Christopher Xie

CONTACT Information

E-mail: chrisxie@cs.washington.edu
Website: https://chrisdxie.github.io/

RESEARCH Interests My interests span the intersection of machine learning, computer vision, and robotics. In particular, I am interested in investigating visual representations that enable robots to perform physical tasks such as object manipulation in unstructured and cluttered scenes.

EDUCATION

Ph.D., University of Washington Computer Science and Engineering

Computer Science and Engineering

July 2021

June 2017

Master of Science, University of Washington Computer Science and Engineering

Bachelor of Science, University of California, Berkeley
Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

May 2015

PUBLICATIONS

FiG-NeRF: Figure-Ground Neural Radiance Fields for 3D Object Category Modelling. Christopher Xie, Keunhong Park, Ricardo Martin Brualla, Matthew Brown.

International Conference on 3D Vision - 3DV, 2021.

RICE: Refining Instance Masks in Cluttered Environments with Graph Neural Networks.

Christopher Xie, Arsalan Mousavian, Yu Xiang, Dieter Fox.

Conference on Robot Learning - CoRL, 2021.

Predicting Stable Configurations for Semantic Placement of Novel Objects.

Chris Paxton, Christopher Xie, Tucker Hermans, Dieter Fox.

Conference on Robot Learning - CoRL, 2021.

Unseen Object Instance Segmentation for Robotic Environments.

Christopher Xie, Yu Xiang, Arsalan Mousavian, Dieter Fox.

IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO), 2021.

Learning RGB-D Feature Embeddings for Unseen Object Instance Segmentation.

Yu Xiang, Christopher Xie, Arsalan Mousavian, Dieter Fox.

Conference on Robot Learning - CoRL, 2020.

Amodal 3D Reconstruction for Robotic Manipulation via Stability and Connectivity.

William Agnew, Christopher Xie, Aaron Walsman, Octavian Murad, Caelen Wang, Pedro Domingos, Siddhartha Srinivasa.

Conference on Robot Learning - CoRL, 2020. Oral Presentation.

ICML Workshop on Object-Oriented Learning, 2020. Spotlight.

The Best of Both Modes: Separately Leveraging RGB and Depth for Unseen Object Instance Segmentation.

Christopher Xie, Yu Xiang, Arsalan Mousavian, Dieter Fox.

Conference on Robot Learning - CoRL, 2019.

Object Discovery in Videos as Foreground Motion Clustering.

Christopher Xie, Yu Xiang, Zaid Harchaoui, Dieter Fox.

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition - CVPR, 2019.

A Simple Adaptive Tracker with Reminiscences.

Christopher Xie, Emily Fox, Zaid Harchaoui.

IEEE Int. Conf. on Robotics and Automation - ICRA, 2019.

NonSTOP: A NonSTationary Online Prediction Method for Time Series.

Christopher Xie, Avleen Bijral, Juan Lavista Ferres.

IEEE Signal Processing Letters, 2018.

A Unified Framework for Long Range and Cold Start Forecasting of Seasonal Profiles in Time Series.

Christopher Xie, Alex Tank, Alec Greaves-Tunnell, Emily Fox.

arXiv:1710.08473, 2017.

NeurIPS Time Series Workshop, 2016. Best Oral Presentation.

Model-based Reinforcement Learning with Parametrized Physical Models and Optimism-Driven Exploration.

Christopher Xie, Teodor Moldovan, Sergey Levine, Sachin Patil, Pieter Abbeel.

IEEE Int. Conf. on Robotics and Automation - ICRA, 2016.

Toward Asymptotically Optimal Motion Planning for Kinodynamic Systems using a Two-Point Boundary Value Problem Solver.

Christopher Xie, Jur van den Berg, Sachin Patil, Pieter Abbeel.

IEEE Int. Conf. on Robotics and Automation - ICRA, 2015.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Washington - Seattle, WA

September 2015 - July 2021

Graduate Research Assistant.

Developed novel deep architectures for unseen object instance segmentation.

Investigated 3D representations for robot manipulation.

Explored prediction methods for online and cold start time series.

Google - Seattle, WA

July 2020 - June 2021

Research Intern/Student Researcher, Google Research

Worked on 3D category-level object modeling.

NVIDIA – Seattle, WA

March 2018 - September 2018

Robotics Research Intern. NVIDIA Robotics Research Lab

Worked on discovering unseen objects in novel environments.

Microsoft - Redmond, WA

June 2016 - September 2016

Research Intern, Consumer Data and Analytics

Worked on Online Learning methods for Forecasting Nonstationary Time Series.

Google – Mountain View, CA

May 2015 - August 2015

Software Engineering Intern, Project Aura

Worked on Google Glass (now known as Project Aura).

University of California, Berkeley - Berkeley, CA

September 2013 - August 2015

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Developed novel motion planning and model-based reinforcement learning algorithms by exploiting

recent tools such as sequential convex programming and optimism-driven exploration.

eBay, Inc. – San Jose, CA

May 2013 - August 2013

Applied Research Intern, Trust Science

Trained neural network and decision tree models to classify fraudulent activity using features extracted from clickstream data only. Optimized them to prevent loss from fraud.

International Computer Science Institute - Berkeley, CA

April 2012 - April 2013

Student Researcher, Artificial Intelligence Group

FrameNet: Developed software to collect crowdsourced data from Amazon Mechanical Turk.

MetaNet: Collaborated with linguists to create a Russian metaphor search using parsed Russian sentences to extract verb-noun relations and clustering algorithms to search for potential new metaphors.

INVITED TALKS

Discovering and Segmenting Unseen Objects in the Absence of Manual Supervision

Facebook AI Research	April 2021
Facebook Reality Labs Research	April 2021
Qualcomm	April 2021
Amazon	April 2021
DeepMind	May 2021

Invited Panelist

Object Representations for Learning and Reasoning Workshop @ NeurIPS.

December 2020

Teaching Robots to be as Smart as Infants.

Honda Research Institute Curious Minded Machines Workshop

October 2019

A Unified Framework for Missing Data and Cold Start Prediction for Time Series Data.

NeurIPS Time Series Workshop, 2016.

December 2016

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Washington – Seattle, WA

Teaching Assistant, CSE571: Robotics	Spring 2020
Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning Coursera Specialization	Winter 2016

University of California, Berkeley - Berkeley, CA

Teaching Assistant, CS189: Introduction to Machine Learning Spring 2014, Spring 2015

Honors and	RSS Pioneers 2021 Cohort	2021
Awards	ICRA 2019 RAS Travel Award	2019
	Best Oral Presentation at NIPS 2016 Time Series Workshop	2016
	National Defense Science and Engineering Graduate (NDSEG) Fellowship	2016
	CSE Educators Endowed Fellowship in Computer Science & Engineering (UW)	2015
	Draper Laboratory Fellowship (declined)	2015
	Eta Kappa Nu Membership	
	Student Member of IEEE	

Advising

Yang Wang (UW undergrad, Sept 2018 - June 2019) Jason Xie (UW undergrad, Sept 2019 - June 2020) Mino Nakura (UW undergrad, Sept 2020 - Present) PROFESSIONAL Paper Reviewing:

ACTIVITIES IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)

IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)

International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)

IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)

IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)

HOBBIES Taekwondo: Received medals from many national and international tournaments. Member of the

Alternate Junior National Team in 2010.

Music: Played keyboard in multiple bands, performed all over the Bay Area.